{
    "id": "dab8f98b7efe4c5d8992e2c11d97fe20",
    "title": "Prepositions quiz",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We may play football. It depends ......................... the weather.",
            "description": "Depend and dependent take the preposition 'on'.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "of",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3d66e4666b744bf8b1b27ce36ce8cad2"
        },
        {
            "question": "We want to see a big increase .................... productivity.",
            "description": "Increase is followed by 'in', not 'of' or 'with'",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "in",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a3f6ac4a19a3446ab982b21af740780f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Excuse me, sir. You haven't ............................ your drink.",
            "description": "We pay 'for' something that is bought.",
            "answers": [
                "pay",
                "paid",
                "paid for"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "81035b6276f645cd8de3abfab4185055"
        },
        {
            "question": "His wife is suffering .............................. hepatitis.",
            "description": "Suffer is followed by the preposition 'from'.",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "with",
                "from"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0642399cd084467db657d3165269e4f9"
        },
        {
            "question": "I hate the thought .......................... going back to work.",
            "description": "The correct expression is 'the thought of'.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "of",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f1bd6e452ae04f23a3f5f975e9fb8a71"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am sorry ............................. breaking your window.",
            "description": "Sorry can be followed by for or about.",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "about",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "db8f972887984d5eb111d3de54c74d5f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is responsible ............................. the shopping this week?",
            "description": "The words responsible and responsibility are followed by 'for'.",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "for",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4f63c823ef404926a982cdabe8bf1352"
        },
        {
            "question": "You remind me ............................ a boy I was at school with.",
            "description": "We use remind...of to say that something makes us remember the past.",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8f4a66180de349e1bf52ebdafaf05eb3"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am pleased ........................... my exam results.",
            "description": "We can be pleased with / about / at something, but we can only be pleased with somebody. ",
            "answers": [
                "with",
                "about",
                "at",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "1af76d0845d64f75b5b6a33e464b3b41"
        },
        {
            "question": "The noise from upstairs prevented me .........................",
            "description": "Note the pattern: prevent ... from ... ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to sleep",
                "from sleeping",
                "from sleep"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "261cdf6aaec7449392893eaf6dd9209d"
        },
        {
            "question": "She insisted ........................... paying for the drinks.",
            "description": "Insist is followed by 'on'. ",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "for",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b511d417ac734b28a2d3ec416f3ac0e0"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am having difficulty .......................... my visa processing.",
            "description": "We can have difficulty with something and difficulty in doing something. ",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "with",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c979794a28af4bc4924451510ab31a80"
        }
    ]
}